<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tidb-academies on PingCAP Site</title>
    <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tidb-academies on PingCAP Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/README/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/README/</guid>
      <description>TiDB Academy Distributed Database with TiDB for MySQL DBAs  Introduction:
 Course Overview Format and Housekeeping Setting up Google Cloud Platform Introduction to Distributed Databases  TiDB Overview:
 TiDB Platform Optional Components: TiSpark The KOST Stack Lab: Deploying TiDB Platform on GKE Recap: Deployng TiDB Platform on GKE  MySQL Compatibility:
 Overview Behavior Differences Default Differences Lab: Loading Sample Data Recap: Loading Sample Data  Query Optimization:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/TODO/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/TODO/</guid>
      <description>Some raw ideas:
 Vision Physical and Logical Optimizer Optimizing Region Placement  Ensuring Geographic Redundancy Range Partitioning  The slow query log Security  grpc protocol no TDE uses mysql privilege system default grant is root no password    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/_google_shell_tutorials/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/_google_shell_tutorials/notes/</guid>
      <description>A full sample data import takes too long for the labs:
 The example from the manual is 2010-2017 = 32m 31s 2016-2017 = 12m23.285s minutes (more suitable for labs) (1.1GB) 2017 only = 6m27.179s (600MB only)  We can possibly switch back to using the full data set after lightning becomes stable. The issue would still be DDL performance though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/profile/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/rocksdb/architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/rocksdb/architecture/</guid>
      <description>Architecture  Resources  Write Ahead Log SST MemTable Bloom Filter  Transcript In this video, we are going to provide a brief introduction to how RocksDB works. Or even more specifically, how an LSM tree works, which is the basic data structure of RocksDB, which differs from InnoDB that uses a B+tree. We will also look at the filesystem to explain what you are seeing in TiKV&amp;rsquo;s data directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup and Restore</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/backup/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/backup/overview/</guid>
      <description>Backup and Restore  Transcript You can&amp;rsquo;t be a DBA without knowing how to backup and restore. It is one of the fundamental skills of database administration, and in this lesson we are going to be taking a closer look.
But before we dive too deep, I want to take a step back and describe some of the fundamentals behind a High Availability and Disaster Recovery plan.
TiKV provides High Availability (HA) natively out of the box, ensuring three copies of each Region are retained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Overview</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/introduction/course-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/introduction/course-overview/</guid>
      <description>Course Overview  Transcript Welcome to TiDB Academy!
My name is Morgan, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be your instructor for TiDB for MySQL DBAs. To give myself a quick introduction, like you I have a background in MySQL Administration. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it for over 15 years now, most recently I was product manager for the MySQL Server at Oracle. If you have a question about how something you do in MySQL works in TiDB, I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to provide an answer!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Summary</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/conclusion/course-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/conclusion/course-summary/</guid>
      <description>Course Summary  Transcript Thank you for joining me on our TiDB for MySQL DBAs course. I hope you had as much fun attending the course, as I did creating it.
In this video, I wanted to go over some of the major takeaways for each of the sections of the course. The goal in me doing so is that if I trigger something that is less familiar to you, you can use this as an opportunity to go back and watch the section again, or repeat the lab exercises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy KOST Stack on GKE</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/tidb-overview/lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/tidb-overview/lab/</guid>
      <description>Deploy KOST Stack on GKE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EXPLAIN</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/query-optimization/explain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/query-optimization/explain/</guid>
      <description>EXPLAIN  Resources  Using EXPLAIN manual page  Transcript Welcome back. In the previous video, I compared query optimization to GPS navigation and an address to being the same as an SQL query. To extend that analogy just a little bit further: a GPS navigation system may have multiple routes to navigate you to the same address. In query optimization parlance, we would say that there are multiple possible execution plans for a query.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding the Busiest Day of the Year</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/htap/TODO/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/htap/TODO/</guid>
      <description>Finding the Busiest Day of the Year In this query, we are finding the day of the year that had the highest number of bike trips:
MySQL [bikeshare]&amp;gt; SELECT COUNT(*) c, DATE(start_date) as day_of_year FROM trips GROUP BY day_of_year ORDER BY c DESC LIMIT 10; +-------+-------------+ | c | day_of_year | +-------+-------------+ | 16896 | 2017-04-15 | | 16346 | 2017-08-05 | | 16191 | 2017-03-25 | | 16038 | 2017-04-14 | | 15767 | 2017-07-30 | | 15549 | 2017-07-26 | | 15517 | 2017-07-08 | | 15477 | 2017-10-07 | | 15434 | 2017-04-13 | | 15403 | 2017-07-04 | +-------+-------------+ 10 rows in set (4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Format and Housekeeping</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/introduction/format-and-housekeeping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/introduction/format-and-housekeeping/</guid>
      <description>Format and Housekeeping  Transcript Before we get deep in the weeds, I want to cover some housekeeping items.
Starting off, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the format. TiDB for MySQL DBAs uses a combination of videos and hands-on exercises. You will need a Google Cloud Platform, or GCP, account in order to complete the tutorials, and a Google Kubernetes Engine cluster of 3x n1-standard instances. GCP comes with a $300 credit for the first year of usage, which is more than enough to complete this course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Cloud Platform</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/introduction/google-cloud-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/introduction/google-cloud-platform/</guid>
      <description>Google Cloud Platform Sign up for a $300 free trial for Google Cloud Platform.
A valid credit card is required. Provided you complete the course in a short enough time frame, your credit card will not be charged. PingCAP is not responsible for any usage fees incurred.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google&#39;s F1 DDL Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/ddl/f1-ddl-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/ddl/f1-ddl-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>Google&amp;rsquo;s F1 DDL Algorithm  Resources  F1 Paper  Transcript So in our previous video, I asserted that DDL in TiDB is both online, and despite being a distributed system, is able to externalize schema changes everywhere at the same time. So how does it work?
The short version is that TiDB uses the methodology described in Google&amp;rsquo;s Online, Asynchronous Schema Change in F1 paper. Let me try and summarize the methodology using an analogy:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTAP</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/htap/lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/htap/lab/</guid>
      <description>HTAP</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTAP</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/htap/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/htap/overview/</guid>
      <description>HTAP  Transcript Welcome back.
A few sections back we talked about query optimization, and the examples used mostly fit into the category of what we call OLTP or online transaction processing.
In this section we, are going to talk about a different type of query, which is used as part of a business&amp;rsquo; reporting needs or decision support systems. These queries tend to be more expensive to execute as they often read a lot of data and aggregate it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horizontal Scaling</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/scaling/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/scaling/overview/</guid>
      <description>Horizontal Scaling  Transcript Welcome back. In this video, we are going to talk about scaling, which for the TiDB platform you can independently perform across two different dimensions.
First, you can scale the SQL processing by changing the number of TiDB Servers. Since TiDB servers are stateless, this is a very quick operation, both in terms of scaling out by increasing the count of TiDB instances and in terms of scaling in by decreasing the count.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Distributed Databases</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/introduction/distributed-databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/introduction/distributed-databases/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Distributed Databases  Transcript In introducing TiDB, I want to start by taking a quick tour of databases and answer what TiDB is, and why it exists.
Our story begins in the 1960s with the first generation of databases. They were not yet relational, and the query language that was used to access records was closely tied to the storage format. So this meant that there was very little in the way of vendor independence, and changing the storage format (perhaps to add an optimization) necessitated changing how you accessed the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Recap: Query Optimization</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/query-optimization/lab-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/query-optimization/lab-recap/</guid>
      <description> Lab Recap: Query Optimization  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Recap: TiDB Platform Lab</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/tidb-overview/lab-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/tidb-overview/lab-recap/</guid>
      <description> Lab Recap: TiDB Platform Lab  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load Sample Data</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/mysql-compatibility/lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/mysql-compatibility/lab/</guid>
      <description>Load Sample Data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrations</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/upgrades/migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/upgrades/migration/</guid>
      <description>Migrations  Resources  ProxySQL mirroring pt-upgrade  Transcript A migration is similar to an upgrade, in that it typically happens on a less sensitive timeframe, but also in that as well as bringing great new features; there is a higher chance there may be performance or functionality regressions.
When we talk about performance in a very broad sense, with users interacting with databases, they tend to feel the variance and not the mean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/monitoring/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/monitoring/overview/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring  Resources  Raft Consensus  Transcript In this section we are going to cover two topics which often get grouped together. Monitoring is about detecting problems and anomalies. Observability is about looking into the system and being able to see how it operates. Most systems can be monitored, but not all are necessarily designed to be observed. If we use a microscope as an analogy, observability is the slide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySQL Compatibility</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/mysql-compatibility/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/mysql-compatibility/overview/</guid>
      <description>MySQL Compatibility  Resources  MySQL Compatibility TiDB Roadmap  Transcript What does it mean to be compatible with MySQL? First, I think it is important to clarify that MySQL is a moving target, as newer versions are released, new features will be added, and existing features may change slightly. In some specific cases, features may also be removed. For example, in MySQL 8.0, weaker crypto functions like ENCODE/DECODE were removed and this has been previously deprecated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observability</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/monitoring/observability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/monitoring/observability/</guid>
      <description>Observability  Resources  Prometheus Grafana  Transcript If you come from a MySQL background, the built-in system for observability is performance_schema. There are some secondary observability commands, but in recent MySQL releases, this has become the gold standard.
Performance Schema is implemented as a storage engine inside of MySQL. Recent MySQL servers are very well instrumented with Performance Schema too: any time the server is allocating memory, waiting on locks or performing I/O: you can query that with regular SQL and find out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observing TiDB Cluster Metrics</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/monitoring/lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/monitoring/lab/</guid>
      <description>Observing TiDB Cluster Metrics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online DDL</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/ddl/lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/ddl/lab/</guid>
      <description>Online DDL</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optional Components: TiSpark</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/tidb-overview/optional-components-tispark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/tidb-overview/optional-components-tispark/</guid>
      <description>Optional Components: TiSpark  Transcript In the last video, we talked about the three core components that make up the TiDB Platform:
 TiKV for distributed storage The TiDB server for SQL processing PD for cluster management  There is one additional component to the TiDB Platform which you can considered optional, and that&amp;rsquo;s TiSpark.
TiSpark allows you to bypass the SQL layer and have Apache Spark connect to TiKV directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Placement Driver</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/scaling/pd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/scaling/pd/</guid>
      <description> Placement Driver  Resources  pd-ctl  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Query Optimization</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/query-optimization/lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/query-optimization/lab/</guid>
      <description>Query Optimization</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Query Optimization</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/query-optimization/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/query-optimization/overview/</guid>
      <description>Query Optimization  Transcript When you look at a query, such as SELECT * FROM trips WHERE bike_id = &#39;x&#39;, you can&amp;rsquo;t actually tell if it executes efficiently. This is because SQL is declarative and it defines what the result or the output should look like. It is not procedural or a set of steps on how to produce that result. For example, do x, then do y, then combine the two.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recap: Backup and Restore</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/backup/backup-and-restore-lab-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/backup/backup-and-restore-lab-recap/</guid>
      <description> Recap: Backup and Restore  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recap: HTAP</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/htap/lab-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/htap/lab-recap/</guid>
      <description> Recap: HTAP  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recap: Load Sample Data Lab</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/mysql-compatibility/lab-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/mysql-compatibility/lab-recap/</guid>
      <description> Recap: Load Sample Data Lab  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recap: Prometheus and Grafana</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/monitoring/lab-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/monitoring/lab-recap/</guid>
      <description> Recap: Prometheus and Grafana  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recap: Restore from Accidental Delete</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/backup/restore-from-accidental-delete-lab-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/backup/restore-from-accidental-delete-lab-recap/</guid>
      <description> Recap: Restore from Accidental Delete  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recap: Scaling</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/scaling/lab-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/scaling/lab-recap/</guid>
      <description> Recap: Scaling  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recap: Schema Changes</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/ddl/lab-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/ddl/lab-recap/</guid>
      <description> Recap: Schema Changes  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recover from Disaster</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/backup/backup-and-restore-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/backup/backup-and-restore-lab/</guid>
      <description>Recover from Disaster</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restore from Accidental Delete</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/backup/restore-from-accidental-delete-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/backup/restore-from-accidental-delete-lab/</guid>
      <description>Restore from Accidental Delete</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RocksDB</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/rocksdb/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/rocksdb/overview/</guid>
      <description>RocksDB  Transcript As I mentioned in our first introduction to TiKV, the storage is based on RocksDB. In fact, you could consider TiKV to be the equivalent to be &amp;ldquo;distributed RocksDB with built-in replication&amp;rdquo;.
So what is RocksDB? RocksDB is the MySQL equivalent of InnoDB. It is an embedded database library developed by the team at Facebook, who forked an earlier database named LevelDB (developed by Google).
In MySQL you can choose between various storage engine options, such as InnoDB or MyISAM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RocksDB Configuration</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/rocksdb/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/rocksdb/configuration/</guid>
      <description>RocksDB Configuration Resources  Tune TiKV  Transcript Under the hood, it is worth noting that each TiKV server instance uses two instances of RocksDB. The default instance is storing your used data, with the second storing the Raft logs (used for distributed consensus between TiKV servers).
Data is organized into Column Families, which in MySQL terminology you can think of as similar to Table Partition, with the exception that instead of a table being partitioned horizontally by rows, it is being partitioned and grouped into sets of columns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Patterns</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/scaling/patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/scaling/patterns/</guid>
      <description>Scaling Patterns  Transcript So in just a second, we will have a lab where we will scale out both TiDB and TiKV, but before we get there, I wanted to cover at a higher level when you would scale one over the other, as well as other performance considerations.
So let&amp;rsquo;s go over some scenarios:
 TiDB servers are stateless. They make heavy use of CPUs and memory, and if you notice you are constrained on either, it might be time to scale out and add additional servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling TiDB</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/scaling/lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/scaling/lab/</guid>
      <description>Scaling</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schema Changes</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/ddl/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/ddl/overview/</guid>
      <description>Schema Changes  Transcript Welcome back.
Recent versions of MySQL have improved support for making schema changes, or DDL. For example, you can add indexes online, which means that while the index is being added, other users of the system can still read and write to the table. There are some limitations to this - for example, not all DDL changes are online. If you wanted to change a column from an integer to a bigint, that would require the table to be locked so that no write operations can occur during this operation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coprocessor</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/query-optimization/coprocessor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/query-optimization/coprocessor/</guid>
      <description>The Coprocessor  Transcript Welcome back. Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve had a chance to experiment with EXPLAIN, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the coprocessor in more detail. For performance reasons, TiDB pushes parts of the query execution down to TiKV for coprocessing. This saves on copying data around which tends to be inefficient. So to revisit our earlier query, we can say that the coprocessor supports the count(*) function:
EXPLAIN SELECT count(*) FROM trips WHERE start_date BETWEEN &amp;#39;2017-07-01 00:00:00&amp;#39; AND &amp;#39;2017-07-01 23:59:59&amp;#39;; I am also going to drop the index start_date which was added earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The KOST Stack</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/tidb-overview/the-kost-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/tidb-overview/the-kost-stack/</guid>
      <description>The KOST Stack  Transcript In MySQL, you have the LAMP stack. With MongoDB there is the MEAN stack. So what is the KOST Stack?
Because the TiDB Platform uses a component based architecture, we have some choices as to how we deploy it. KOST is an infrastructure pattern which consists of Kubernetes, Operator, Spark, and TiDB. We have already introduced the last two letters, so in this video I&amp;rsquo;m going to introduce Kubernetes and Operator:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TiDB &#43; Apache Spark</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/htap/spark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/htap/spark/</guid>
      <description>TiDB + Apache Spark  Transcript For those that are confused with the overlap between the TiDB Server and Apache Spark, which can both execute SQL queries, here is a general rule to differentiate the two:
 TiDB aims to handle 100% of OLTP queries. TiDB aims to handle 80% of adhoc OLAP queries.  Spark has some advantages for very long running queries from its managed execution environment. Jobs can be automatically re-run on failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TiDB Platform</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/tidb-overview/tidb-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/tidb-overview/tidb-platform/</guid>
      <description>TiDB Platform  Transcript When comparing TiDB to MySQL and discussing architecture, not everything is an apples-to-apples comparison. While TiDB speaks the MySQL protocol, it is important to clarify it does not share any MySQL source code in common.
TiDB is a NewSQL database that was inspired by the design of Google&amp;rsquo;s internal Spanner project. It is distributed by design and consists of several components that together make what we call the TiDB Platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TiDB and MySQL: Behavior Differences</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/mysql-compatibility/behavior-differences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/mysql-compatibility/behavior-differences/</guid>
      <description>TiDB and MySQL: Behavior Differences  Resources  MySQL Compatibility Support for built-in JSON functions Support for aggregate functions  Transcript In the previous video, we talked about TiDB compatibility with MySQL and how some features were not present. For example: stored procedures, triggers, views.
Let&amp;rsquo;s now talk about something more subtle: the feature also exists in TiDB, but works differently. In many cases this is TiDB is a distributed database, and needs to work a little bit differently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TiDB and MySQL: Default Differences</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/mysql-compatibility/default-differences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/mysql-compatibility/default-differences/</guid>
      <description>TiDB and MySQL: Default Differences  Resources  MySQL Compatibility  Transcript In the previous video, I talked about TiDB&amp;rsquo;s behavior differences from MySQL. As a follow-on, I&amp;rsquo;m now going to cover differences in defaults between TiDB and MySQL 5.7. This is really an extension of behavior differences, since TiDB is behaving in a way that MySQL does not out of the box, but with a configuration change (either to TiDB or MySQL) the two systems could be made to behave the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/upgrades/updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/upgrades/updates/</guid>
      <description>Updates  Resources Container Definition for TiDB
Transcript So let&amp;rsquo;s discuss updates first. Starting with the lowest level, and working our way up.
In our cloud deployment, patching of the infrastructure, switches, routers, firmware is all handled by Google. Sitting above that is Kubernetes, which is also handled by Google.
We then have the Google Kubernetes Engine and the node pool of VMs running Container-Optimized OS (COS).
We have some flexibility in selecting the master version of the Google Kubernetes Engine (at writing the default is 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates, Upgrades and Migrations</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/upgrades/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/upgrades/overview/</guid>
      <description>Updates, Upgrades and Migrations  Transcript Welcome back.
In this section, we are going to be talking about updates, upgrades, and migrations. To define the terminology:
 An update is a point release, for example, from TiDB 2.0.4 to 2.0.7. Updates are always expected to be safe to perform, and contain fixes to critical bugs (either security of functionality). They typically will not contain new functionality or changes to behaviors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrades</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/upgrades/upgrades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/upgrades/upgrades/</guid>
      <description>Upgrades  Transcript Upgrades are often less time sensitive or critical than updates.
Rather than the motivation being security updates as it is with updates, an upgrade is more forward looking and strategic. The motivation could be for improved compatibility with MySQL, performance enhancements, or an entirely new feature.
In the case of TiDB, you may be planning your upgrade from TiDB 2.0 to 2.1.
Using this as an example, an upgrade to 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Next?</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/conclusion/whats-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/conclusion/whats-next/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s Next?  Resources  Course Survey TiDB on GKE Marketplace (Coming Soon) Official TiDB Certification Exam Sign Up Form Private TiDB Training  Transcript You&amp;rsquo;ve now completed TiDB Academy&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;TiDB for MySQL DBAs&amp;rdquo; course. You might be wondering, what&amp;rsquo;s next?
First things first, we&amp;rsquo;d love to get your feedback on your experience with this course. Please take this 2-minute survey and you&amp;rsquo;ll enter a raffle automatically for a $40 Amazon gift card.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XXXX</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/_google_shell_tutorials/template/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/tidb-academy/mysql_dbas/_google_shell_tutorials/template/</guid>
      <description> XXXXX Introduction Using your previously deployed Kubernetes Cluster, we will complete the following steps:
 XXX XXXX Restore from backup  Recheck Configuration You should already have a .bashrc file configuring your defaults. Create a tunnel to TiDB:
establish-port-forward If you see -bash: establish-port-forward: command not found, reload the setup tutorial and make sure your environment is configured correctly.
XXX </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>